You may be seated.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Viewers all over the world, thank you for your time.
TALK ON FAITH
The reality of faith can only be proved by practice.
The reality of faith can only be proved by what?
[By practice.]
If you say you have faith, you should not just only believe in Him.
Tell your neighbour, "If you say you have faith, you should not just only believe in Him".
If somebody says, "I believe God", where is your faith?
You say, "I believe God, I am a Christian".
Where is your faith?
Faith must be practised.
We should not merely talk about faith; we should put it into practice because faith is a conviction.
That is faith.
Our works prove our faith.
Your work proves your faith.
Are you doing "419", you know how to play people to gain or to deceive people?
Your work perfects or completes your faith.
It means if you don’t have good works, you don’t have faith.
Only faith pleases God.
Nothing.
Our works prove our faith.
Our works perfect or complete our faith.
Let me start from African countries.
Sometimes, when I see what is happening around the world, I keep quiet.
Even the revelation for the year - I refuse to release it.
I decided to do that.
I think that position is better.
That position is better to pray for the whole world.
The Bible says where there is no vision, people perish.
What has happened to my people in DRC - Congo.
I think it was three years ago when I was invited to that country, to see the president.
I prayed.
I said - to travel to DRC to see the president, the Head of State...
I went through the letter and said, "OK, I must go".
I prayed over it.
God said that He would give me a message to deliver.
"If you say you are going, do you have a message to deliver now?"
I said, "No".
"So, you have to wait for the message."
I said, "OK".
It is true - I am not going there to pray.
I should go there to deliver a message.
If I say that I will travel there because I am a man of God and I am going to pray...
After a prayer, there must be a revelation but for now - no revelation.
That was three years ago.
I said, "OK".
I then decided to send my team.
I raised a team of three, four, five from different countries to visit the nation and the president.
I asked them to greet the president.
I was not trying to be proud.
Who I am - I am just a human being but as a man of God, I must have a revelation before I move.
I just wanted to honour the invitation because I was not able to go there.
OK, my people went there - good.
They received them joyfully as visitors to the Head of State.
They delivered my message and came back.
The delegation from this country also came here with joy to visit us - OK.
I said, "Before God will release me to come to your country, this is the message:
By February, there will be trouble".
That was three years ago.
I said the trouble would start from February and I stated those troubles that would start,
which they took home and delivered to the nation.
The reason I am saying this is that
I am worried; I am not comfortable because of what is happening around the world.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
This will happen; that will happen, by February.
The whole thing will start unfolding and there will be a crisis.
Let's start our prayer from the country.
Rise up and let us pray for the nation because the crisis is coming.
I want you to do it with all your heart.
Don't say it is not your country - any country is your country.
Open your heart and pray for God's intervention in the nation, Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC).
Prayer For God's Intervention In The Nation Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC)
God's intervention – because I am seeing trouble coming – big trouble.
God's intervention.
Prayer For God's Intervention In The Nation Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC)
God's intervention in the nation, Congo - DRC.
In Jesus Christ's name we pray.
[Amen.]
I am saying this because with what is happening now,
what I saw in the vision today again, my heart is bleeding.
I know, with God, all things are possible.
God will redeem the nation and citizens in Jesus' name.
[Amen.]
You may be seated.
You will join me to pray for many countries today.
Let's now go to Southern Africa.
I am seeing some natural disasters like wind – bad wind coming from the sea -
bad nature – natural disasters that will destroy many things, that will move from one country to another.
I saw this – that was the last two years.
We keep praying but there is a momentum in the sea which will look strange,
which has never happened in Africa.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The whole thing will arrange from the Mozambique area.
Poor people live in environments where all these things will happen -
people who will not have a place to go; they will become refugees.
Poor people who are looking for shelter to stay -
they are the ones living in ninety percent of the environment I am talking about.
This thing will move from country to country.
I don't want to mention any county.
Let us rise up and pray for part of Southern Africa -
moving from countries like Mozambique, South Africa, Botswana and some areas there.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Why am I calling for your attention to this?
I have been praying.
God said, "Call the attention of your people".
Let's pray together because of the Hosts of Heaven, the atmosphere we are in.
Whatever we loose shall be loosed, whatever we bind shall be bound.
Open your lips for prayer.
Prayer For God's Intervention In Countries of Southern Africa
In Jesus Christ's name we pray.
[Amen.]
Let there be calmness!
Wherever this nature – tragedy in the sea, air, rainy season, dry season -
this bad nature that is coming – let there be calmness, in the name of Jesus!
[Amen.]
Jesus said to the sea and wind, "Be calm!"
Let there be calmness, in the name of Jesus!
[Amen.]
What Africa depends on at this time is farming and it will greatly affect the farmers,
cattle rearers – all these will be affected, greatly.
Let there be calmness, in the name of Jesus!
[Amen.]
The SCOAN Sunday Service
As you are praying, add Ethiopia as a nation.
Remember the nation Ethiopia in prayer.
Pray against famine – serious one.
What is the cause of this? Because of season – unpredictable.
Open your lips and pray for the country Ethiopia.
Prayer For God's Intervention In The Country Ethiopia
In Jesus Christ's name.
[Amen.]
Open your lips and pray with me: You, wind, we say, be calm!
Let there be calmness, in the name of Jesus!
You, wind, you, disaster of any kind – be calm, in the name of Jesus!
We cannot let this thing to disturb us - they will have to go back the way they came.
We say, calmness, in the name of Jesus!
Anytime you pray, please remember this country.
It is not that other countries don't have their own challenges but I'm seeing this natural disaster.
You may be seated.
Now, back to my nation, Nigeria.
The last two years, there was a vision, a prophecy for the nation, which is still going on.
It's not only for last year but still for this year.
It is still going on 'til June.
This is why God said, "Hold on. What you said two years ago that there will be scarcity of food
and devaluation of money and we are in the valley – that was two years ago -
and our future is crying for help, will end this coming June".
We are in February now.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
By the time we leave June, we know all those prophecies I said about food scarcity, devaluation of money...
Because this money will still continue going up and it will seem to rest when it is getting to 650.
It will seem to begin to rest; it will not be able to go forward.
It will not be able to go forward because that will be the peak.
The battle of going up, down, up, down will continue but when it gets to that,
it will not be able to go up again; rather, it will want to go down, if the system permits -
if the system agrees with divine will.
I was saying something which you didn't take note of and I want to repeat that.
Your president has good intentions.
I repeat again.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Good intentions cannot be carried out alone without good followers.
If you heard what I said - it is OK.
But even Mr. T.B. Joshua may have heard what Prophet T.B. Joshua was saying as a human being.
Two persons are standing here.
Mr. T.B. Joshua may hate Prophet for what he is saying.
If Mr. hates the Prophet - if you hate me, there is nothing bad about that.
I repeat again.
Your president has good intentions but good intentions cannot be carried out alone without good followers.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The priority of every Nigerian citizen now is the good health of your president.
It can be anyone’s turn tomorrow.
What you wish for others, God makes happen to you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We rise up together and pray – with all your heart.
I want us to rise up – with all your heart.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Ask God to give him whatever he needs.
Because you have not heard anything, whatever you believe he needs
for the strength and enablement to rule successfully, the Lord should give him. Prayer.
Prayer For The Nigerian President
Strength where there is weakness – enablement, in Jesus Christ’s name.
[Amen.]
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You may be seated.
Thank you for the prayer.
More importantly, we have to rise up that the Lord should give the grace to sustain democracy.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Rise up for prayer.
Grace for democratic sustainability. Prayer.
Prayer Of Grace For Democratic Sustainability
Pray for uninterrupted democracy.
Prayer.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
In Jesus Christ’s name we pray.
[Amen.]
The SCOAN Sunday Service
No nation is ruled successfully without good institutions.
Africa as a whole - we only look for leaders, we don't look for institutions.
We don't mind about institutions, we are looking for leaders.
Leaders cannot rule alone, without good institutions.
The whole Africa lacks institutions.
They have leaders but leaders cannot do it alone.
It is like a prophet without disciples.
It is not a "one day job" for a prophet to have disciples.
This is why everywhere in Africa they want to run for power two times.
Their first time seems to be rubbish because they use strangers to work with them.
By the second time they would have studied those who can work with them and do good.
Every African leader does better the second time because they didn't have good disciples
to work with them during the "first time".
People working with leaders during the "first time" are donors -
they support them, give leaders money, pray for them
but they are not real disciples - they just give help, financial and moral support.
By the time the leader becomes a president, he calls his supporters to give them positions.
But the leaders don't really know them by their character.
They receive positions just because they helped.
So, the "first time" is always nonsense in every African country
because they seem to use strangers to work with them.
In the "second time", they would have studied people and know, "Oh, really! This is my disciple"
and put them into positions. They do better during their "second time".
I'm not studying government - I'm just telling you the mind of God.
If any leader comes to the office for the first time and says that he would do everything,
he would do this, he would do that,
I just look - "Can you do it alone?"
You are coming for the first time - for how long have you known the people working with you?
Do you know them by their relationships and character?
How do you know that these people will be loyal to you?
Just because they helped you...
If you give money to someone, it does not mean that he is your friend.
You can give money to your enemy.
You can even help your enemy.
It does not mean that he is a man of your own heart.
That you give millions, trillions to someone does not mean that he is your friend.
Those are the challenges African countries are facing today.
When Africa begins to think about institutions...
There should be a school or university for leaders to go to before they can become this or that.
So, anyone who becomes a president of a nation must have his disciples as well to join him to rule.
If not, whatever he promises will fail.
This is why the "second time" of any leader in Africa seems to do better.
By the "second time", they would have chosen better people they can work with.
They will look for men of their own heart.
This is what is happening all over Africa.
Now, the same thing is going on all over the world.
Not only in Africa but all over the world.
People don't look for a man of their own heart to work with them;
they just call people because they donate millions to support them.
They support them in their campaigns.
They work harder.
They call them to their cabinet to work - it does not mean that this man can be a man of your own heart.
You may be seated. Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Take note of these words I said just now.
Leaders seem to use men who are not of their own heart.
To have a man of your own heart is not a day's job; it's a matter of time and preparation.
To be a minister of this or that...
To be a chairman of this or that...
... and you being the head, and he will be loyal to you.
Your vision will be his vision - it is not easy - it takes time and preparation.
Jesus knew he would not be able to succeed alone; that is why He had 12 disciples.
He knew no one can go it alone.
He knew that as a Saviour he had to look for people to follow Him.
Even among them - you know what happened.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You know what is happening all over the world - not only in politics; even in the house of God.
The cause of churches collapsing is what I am talking about now.
They cannot point to a man of their own heart to do this for them and they cannot do it alone.
Instead, they use their enemies to do this and their enemies crumble their vision.
You know what is happening to your business; you cannot do it alone.
At a time, you wanted to expand but no one was there to help you.
You cannot be in two places at the same time.
You continue to expand where you are.
When you begin to be too popular in a certain place, attack and persecution start.
This is why today you see millionaires who were up there crumble
because they could not find people to carry out their vision.
Branches of their companies – the people that represented those branches crumbled their vision.
When you start to think about expanding - "No, let me remain where I am".
Success does not permit that; success wants to explode.
You can’t light a candle and put it under the roof.
You must bring the candle out and let the world see it.
If you put a candle under the roof, it will burn the house.
If you say you are afraid and you camp that success, you will explode with the success.
The success will consume you.
So, now, what is the way out?
Faith is something that comes spontaneously, naturally – that is faith.
What is the way out?
The way out is . as you are growing, take time to train people and impart to people.
If not, by the time you finish growing and become an iroko tree,
you will not see anyone to help you; you will use your enemy as a helper.
Jesus took time to train people, to impart in them.
And even then - He was betrayed.
But at last, He made the best out of His people.
Take your time to train people.
What do I mean by training?
Allow them to see what you are doing.
Let them see what you are doing, so they can do the same.
As they see what you are doing, your enemies among them will give way
and those men after your own heart will continue to follow you.
Finally when you get there, they can be there to carry the vision.
This is what the world is facing today; there is crisis in this world.
That is why there are no new things coming.
I told you last time that we are running out of ideas.
The world is running out of ideas.
There is no new vision - nothing new.
Science is running out of ideas.
There is no new idea because they are dying with their own ideas.
They cannot impart those ideas to people.
They don't have people of their own heart to work with them.
If you continue to carry it alone, you will get tired.
If this body is tired, you cannot carry out the vision again.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So, like I have said; as you are growing, take your time to grow others.
It's not just to be using them and then giving them money.
We are not talking about money.
You have people working with you - you can pay them a lot of money - that is not the issue.
Money cannot make the vision we are talking about; it's all about sincerity.
You say, "I pay them. I give them huge money. They work with me..."
We are not talking of working with you and giving them money.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
OK, if you are bigger than this tomorrow, how will you maintain that grace?
You alone cannot maintain that position; you need someone to…
And you don’t have any men of your own heart;
you finally find yourself using your enemy to maintain your vision.
Look at universities all over the world or in Nigeria... just university in Nigeria alone.
Do you know what is happening?
Those best universities in the world that we know about in Nigeria.
When you go to their premises or campus, see what is happening...
It is not an issue of money.
But we keep shouting, "Money! There is no money to develop".
It is not an issue of money!
I know money is very important.
It is not an issue of money.
If you look at first class students - very brilliant - and you send them to another country for a program
and another country sends their first class students to that country...
When they come back, they will raise the standard here.
How much does it take to send people to...
And you keep saying, "Money money money".
If there is money and no brain, can money work?
Brain is dying - we are running out of ideas.
You talk of money.
When there is no idea, money is dead; money is useless.
If a man without an idea has money - it is like "mental people" having money - the crazy man.
It is like a very rich man suddenly having a mental problem - it is equal to a rich man running out of ideas.
When you don't have ideas, the money is useless.
It is an idea that makes use of money; it is an idea that spends money.
Where are we going?
That is our education.
Not only in Nigeria - all over the world - just like that.
There are some faculties at universities which need to be increased in number.
But because you are looking for money, you just want to have a university
and you don't mind any course they study. You need money from students.
Whereas there are some important faculties that can build the nation.
Until we begin to separate those faculties...
You have this university, college of medicine; you have this university, law school...
No. You bring all together which destroys university.
There are some students there that "have no brain" - they just go to university to study any course.
Compare it to a subject where you have to have a brain to study it.
You must separate these students in order to build the nation.
But the university of this or college...
When you look at those faculties, they seem to be useless.
These are the faculties that you only spend money on.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When you look at the nation, you will be able to know what the nation needs at that time.
What does this nation, your country, need at this time?
Not until we begin to sort out those faculties, universities - separate them, put them where they belong.
The importance of those faculties...
Know how you can get the money to raise the standard of those faculties to build the nation.
When you build those faculties, you are building the nation.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Many parents don't know their right and left.
They just want their children to go to university.
Fine.
We get money but money without ideas is useless.
So, I think - what we are facing today is that we lack ideas.
People lack ideas but have money.
You can't eat your money.
Your money is not valuable without ideas.
When you ask people a simple question today, they will complain about their government.
Our government doesn't do this or that.
When you don't run out of ideas, you do not have any business with the government -
even the government will want you to help the nation if you have not run out of ideas.
It is when we run out of ideas that we begin to complain about the government.
No money to do this or that - because we are running out of ideas.
You can be so great without the government.
The government will now turn to you for help.
There is a lot of burden on the government because everybody depends on the government.
That is why the world is collapsing.
You depend on the government of your nation to live, which is wrong.
Because we are running out of ideas.
Without a contract from the government, you cannot live.
Without government supporting business, you cannot live.
If there is no budget to give money to everybody, you complain.
This is what we depend on because we are running out of ideas.
Not until people have ideas, you cannot leave this pitiful life.
When trouble comes to the government, it will affect you.
You have to look beyond.
Yes.
Rise up for prayer.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
What is the cause of man running out of ideas?
When you run out of ideas, you begin to look at others to reason and think,
compare yourself to others and measure yourself with others, you are running out of ideas.
You say, "This man is slim - I want to be slim. Look at the hair of this woman - I want the same haircut.
I saw a posh car last week - I want to buy the same car".
You are running out of ideas.
You begin to imitate others to live, talk and even pray.
You look at what people say - you want to say the same because you run out of ideas.
When you run out of ideas, your money is not your money;
your money is someone else's money.
Are you with me?
When you run out of ideas, your possession is not your possession;
it is someone else's possession because you don’t know the use of it.
Someone else will be using your possessions, enjoying what you have.
You go for a medical check-up - little time - sickness, disease, this, that...
They give you this; they give you chieftaincy.
When there is no money, you are not given the chieftaincy. When money comes, they call you for chieftaincies.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Time to ask yourself, "Why did they not call me for chieftaincy when I didn't have money?
But now I have money and they call me for chieftaincy".
You should know that something is wrong somewhere.
"I was not sick when I did not have enough.
But now that I have enough, I'm sick."
What do you think happened then?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
"People call me to invite me, to visit them, to come to a party, from all over the world, because I have...
How do they know that I have?
When I didn't have, nobody invited me, nobody wanted to be my friend."
Can't you ask yourself, "Why?"
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So much responsibility - and this responsibility will take you away from God.
Take note of this once again.
When you run out of ideas, your possession is someone else's possession.
To run out of ideas means when you cannot think right at the right time or do things at the right time.
You may do them but not at the right time.
You move - it is right that you must move but it is at the wrong time.
To do things at the right time gives result.
There is a time for everything.
If you are not standing up for prayer now at the right time, it means God will not connect with us.
You pray at the wrong time.
It's right you are praying but are you praying at the right time?
The Holy Spirit intercedes for us; we don’t know how to pray.
You cannot just stand up and just say, "I want to pray".
If I have faith in God, there will be what?
There will be work that corresponds with the faith.
Tell your neighbour, "If there is faith, there will be work that corresponds with the faith".
Again.
If there is faith, there will be work that corresponds with the faith.
I cannot hear you.
If there is no work that corresponds with the faith...
If work is different from faith - that is, you have bad work.
The work you are doing is not good.
But you have faith - that cannot correspond.
If there is faith, there will be work that corresponds with the faith.
It is like a magnet and a nail.
You have a nail here and you have a magnet here - if you bring them close, they will...
You can see - magnet.
But if it is not a nail, it will not...
If there is faith, there will be work that corresponds with the faith.
If not, you will continue to say, "I am a Christian. I have faith" but this work doesn't correspond with...
This is why when we pray today, our prayer goes nowhere.
We talk to ourselves when we are praying.
"In the name of Jesus" - you are talking to yourself.
Tell your neighbour again:
"If there is faith, there will be work that corresponds with the faith."
This is what I mean by our work proves our faith.
This is what I mean by our work completes or perfects our faith.
If your work does not correspond with your faith, you are faithless.
The faith you are talking about is not faith in God.
There are all kinds of faith but I am talking about faith in God.
Have faith in God
All things are possible
Again.
Have faith in God
All things are possible
Again.
Have faith in God
All things are possible
That is the faith I'm talking about.
Have it in God - the Bible talks about it in Mark.
If there is faith - if you claim you have this faith, there will be work that corresponds with the faith.
You know where your problem comes from now.
You can know where your problem comes from.
Right now, it's a matter of talking with all your heart, confessing with all your heart.
Ask God for His grace; you need His grace.
Open your lips - prayer.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Ask God for His grace.
In the mighty name of Jesus Christ we pray.
[Amen.]
Out of the message I gave you today, take note of one point.
This is the mistake we are doing.
You never believed that your enemy can give you trillions of dollars and yet be your enemy.
You believed that someone giving you a billion dollars loves you with all his heart.
Your enemy can give you trillions of dollars and yet be your enemy.
But you don't know that.
To you; you consider someone giving you so much a man of your own heart - no, my brother!
How do you run your business then?
You run it without ideas because you need money.
Somebody giving you money becomes your dear friend.
We don't go beyond to ask God, "Who is giving me money?"
Do you know that your enemy can establish you?
If you know that raise up your hand.
An enemy can establish you for reasons known to him.
Oh my God.
There are many things that you don't know.
You don't know because you are a business man.
You are a politician.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
This is the reason why you are facing many things.
Think about your track record from the beginning.
Sit down and think about your life.
You will begin to agree with me.
You don't believe that people that have done so much for you can turn round to be your enemies.
They seem to be giving you so much, they seem to establish you - they later turn to be your enemies
at a difficult time, at the time you need them.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I don't want you to get to Heaven before you understand all this.
I don't want you to go to Heaven before you see the file.
"I didn't know that this thing is happening in this world and I was there for many years - see me."
I don't want you to get to Heaven before you understand this; you better understand it now.